CAIMING XIONG: Hello, everyone.
I'm Caiming Xiong.
I'm very glad to get the invite
to present this multimodal agent
areas.
I saw you already listened
the exact same area
as multimodal agent last week.
Hopefully, I would bring
something new in this direction.
So first I want to show
this plot to everyone.
So you can see how crazy it is.
In the past five years,
almost all the benchmarks
get saturated.
And now, we have
the last one, which
is the one proposed this
year, the humans last exam.
Seems like when we solve
this one, we solved AGI.
I'm not sure whether we
can solve it this year,
but I believe we'll have a much
better result for this data set
with benchmarks by
the end of this year.
OK, since we have so powerful
Frontier Foundation models,
then what we should
do on those models?
How we could leverage them
to make our world make
the society better?
I think the answer is agent.
We believe the multimodal AI
agent is the next generation
of applications.
Why?
It's because we want agents,
not just reading text.
We want the agent who can
hear, can see, can speak,
can feel even.
And we want agents that to
process a task like a human,
because most of the tasks
that when we do in computer,
they involve multiple
apps interfaces.
So powered with the
new advanced language
model or the large foundation
model, which is vision language
action models, it could make
the digital interactions
more accessible, more
automated, and increase
the human's productivity.
So what are the status of
the multimodal agent now?
How far it is?
Actually it's not far away.
We already see a lot of
the multimodal agents
being used in a real world.
Or some of them is used in real
world, I would say some of them
in the research.
Like for example,
a coding agent.
I think some of you,
maybe a lot of you,
are using the coding
assistant or agent
products like the
cursor, Replit, or Darwin
in your daily work or research.
And those agents, if not only,
that can accept the code text,
it also can let you
to upload the images.
And they could to
generate the code
or fix your bug through
the images you send.
Web agents-- the
web agents is it's
also a multimodal agent that
the agent could help you,
or could automate some control
in your browser or apps.
Same as the mobile agents
and the even physical agent.
Super amazing, right?
So this is a robot called
Helix from figure AI.
Not just you interact
with a single robot.
Even if that robot and
robot collaborate together
through the powerful
this foundation models.
So all those agents, some of
them in production, some of them
is still in research.
Some of is a demo stage.
And I believe we
are going to have
more and more this
type of applied use
cases of multimodal agents.
So the question is,
how are we going
to develop them, and what are
the challenges for developing
those multimodal
agents, and what
is the important component
what we should focus on?
So this is today's agenda.
I will talk about the multimodal
agents from these three areas.
First is development benchmark.
We need an interactive
environment.
We need this environment can be
more reconfigurable, expandable,
not just static benchmarks
for multimodal agents.
We need the data.
How we get the data to
train our multimodal agents?
The third one is what
model we should build on?
We interact with
computers every day
and use that to perform
a lot of different tasks,
including web browsing,
editing some personal videos,
managing our files,
doing some analyzes,
or doing coding to implement
some software softwares.
It's not just for those tasks.
It's not just to interact
with a single app.
It is a workflow that will
involve multiple applications
through a GUI or CLI.
And with multiple
multimodal agents,
it could have a
big potential that
can help us to revolutionize
this interaction between us
and this computer environment.
The agents can follow our
high level natural language
instruction and to automatically
to do those interactions.
For example, in this
image, in this slide,
there is a task called
the update the bookkeeping
sheet with my
recent transactions
over the past few days
in the provided folder.
It is a very boring task.
For this type of
task, I think everyone
would like to have an agent to
help them process those tasks
if they are available.
However, how can you
trust those agents?
We need to have a benchmark.
So currently, there
is a major challenge
in developing those
multimodal agents.
But we don't have
a benchmark that
depends on the real
interactive environment,
that this environment can cover
the more diverse and complex,
the real world, the
computer use the scenarios,
and also can support the
different operating system
interfaces apps.
So with this type of benchmark,
after the agent passed
that benchmark, we can chart.
We can trust this agent
for our daily use.
So currently, we have
some that already
have some good benchmarks,
but they are not
have these properties
that I just mentioned.
Like, the Mind2Web.
The Mind2Web is a
real good benchmark.
They include a lot
of the real testing.
However, for each
test in the Mind2Web,
it has only single
demonstrations
without the executable
environment.
So the assumption from the
Mind2Web is, for each task
there is only a single solution,
which is not true 100%.
And with that
benchmark, it would
paralyze some alternative
correct solution.
The WebArena is
another good benchmark.
It is an executable environment.
However, it simplified the
observations and action
space that it only
covers very limited,
the task and the
applications or domains
like it only covered web
navigation on a few websites
in domains.
So in that one is restrict
the testing the use cases
for the agents, and also it
cannot use to evaluate some open
manned tasks in a complex
real world scenarios.
Not maybe they require
some tasks, require
the navigating between the
multiple different applications
and interfaces in
the open domain.
To address this gap between the
development, the real world use
case and the model development,
the simulation environment,
we introduce the OSWorld.
This is the first the
scalable and the real computer
environment for development
and the benchmarking
of multimodal agents.
Why?
I would say, it is a real
computer environments.
And it could be used
for the both development
and the benchmarking of
multimodal agents as well
as the OSWorld for the first.
This development allows the
free from the keyboard, mouse
control of the real
computer applications.
And it's not they fixed
the evaluation set.
You could to config your
tasks and execute those tasks
through this interactive way.
So this one, then you
can use the OSWorld
to evaluate some
open-ended computer tasks
and with the arbitrary
applications.
So it's not fixed.
Maybe you can do, ranging
from different use
case like a software development
use case or the image editing
use case.
But also, it can serve
as a unified, real world,
real computer environment
that allows the users--
so in this way, it can allow
users to define a new agent
task without to build this
new domain specific simulation
environment.
So it's either environment, the
Earth world is more flexible
and give the users more control
for the environment design
for the scenarios they can use.
So let's see how are we going
to use the OSWorld to create
the different task.
The first for each task, you
have a natural language task
instruction for the task.
So you see here you have a task.
You want to create this testing
environment like updating--
I just mentioned this task--
updating is bookkeeping sheet.
And with this,
then in the OSWorld
they provide the initial state
setup for this instruction.
So the setup-- it's a you
just need to create this file.
In this file, they include
multiple components.
The red part is you need to
config the initial tasks are
like this Excel files tasks.
And also you need to add
what is your post-processing
and those configurations.
And also, where you can retrieve
the files and the information.
And the yellow part
and the last one
is how you're going to
evaluate after you finish
the task in the environment.
After you configure
your initial state--
the setup-- those words, they
will initialize this environment
with a virtual machine.
And in the virtual machine
they will initialize
though the
initialization, will start
to run in this virtual machine,
and you get the initial states
of the test environment.
That's very convenient.
So for example, at
this moment, you
could use this virtual
machine to restore
the task again and again, just
to reuse this virtual machine.
But because of we use
this virtual machine,
so it's a safe,
isolated environment.
We don't need to worry
about some damage
in irreversible damages
when you do testing.
So when the task
environment gets set up then
you can start to run
your agent to interact
with this environment.
For example, you
can use GPT 4 way
to create an agent and
interact with its environment.
Or you can use any
other open-source model
to build an agent.
The agent will
receive or observe
different information that can
be provided by the environment.
First, of course, is the user
query, the natural language
instruction from the user.
And also, it can
receive the observations
from the environment,
such as the screenshot,
the accessibility tree, and
some customized streams,
maybe the terminal outputs.
So here is an example, the left
side is called a set of mask,
which is a screenshot
plus some x plus--
the information you extract
from accessibility tree
that you can add those
label like in the image,
so they can provide more
information or just screenshot.
And also the right
side is the dormitory.
It is accessibility tree,
but for website it's a DOM 3.
So after the agent receive
those observations, of course,
it's not like every agent
need all the observations.
It depends on your agent.
If you are vision based
agent, maybe you only
use the screenshot or SOM.
If it is a text-based
agent, maybe you
are only use accessibility tree.
It depends on what agent you're
going to build or to interact
with the environment.
So after you receive those
observations, the agent will--
it depends on how
you create agent--
but the agent finally will
generate some actual executable
actions, like you
click some position
or you will drag some
content, drag some box,
et cetera, to manipulate
the keyboard and mouse.
And then, each of
those actions will
be represented
using a code string
and generated by the agent.
And then the simulator will
execute those the code strings
in the virtual machine and you
will get the new observations
now.
The odds were that, we are
using the pi auto GI3 to control
the mouse and keyboard.
This is where we
used the library.
So this interaction
loop will continue
based on your instruction.
We will repeat multiple
steps, and here it terminated.
Maybe it's done
or failed or it's
reached the maximum
number of steps you set.
In our experiment,
we set is 15 and 50.
So now you can setup the
task until you run your task.
And then after the task you
stop, you get the results.
Then you will do evaluation
on your task in this OSWorld.
OSWorld is different
from other benchmarks.
We implement this execution
based on the reward function.
So when the final step
reach the goal, of course,
they will get a positive reward.
Or even if partially
achieved, we
will get some number
between 0 and 1.
If not, it's totally failed.
It will get 0.
To get this reward,
we are not just
use the single
evaluation metric.
So here to evaluate the
successful execution
of those tasks, we thinking
there is no single way
to evaluate the success
or failure for the task.
So we make this
evaluation more open.
So what is open?
So open means that you can
construct the evaluation script
by yourself.
That's really relevant
because some tasks
you need to retrieval, some
tasks you need to matching
to evaluate your task.
So we use this example
wise, the evaluation,
to design the evaluation
metric for the tasks.
So not just the fixed one.
So it's an open one that you
can base on different tasks
to design your different
evaluation metrics,
so that you can facilitate
the diversity of the tasks
and could make the
evaluation more reliable,
especially for this complex,
real world open-ended tasks.
So we created this a
powerful OSWorld Environment,
so that the people can use
this environment to benchmark
in their multimodal agents.
But besides, we built this
environment, of course,
we also built a benchmark
on top of the OSWorld.
Here we introduce the
369 real-world computer
tasks that involve widely
used the web or desktop apps
like the AllFace,
OS, and daily use
workflow and the
professionals, all of them.
Each task, we did a lot
of search on the internet.
So all of them is based on
the real world computer use
cases, the experience.
And we ask the people who
have the CSS background
to interact with the initialize
the environment in OSWorld
and interact with
the environment.
And we call those
the trajectories.
And also handcrafted a lot of
the execution-based evaluation
scripts to verify
the task completion.
So in the left side, you
can see the distribution
of the different tasks.
So total we have 369, and
one hundred is a workflow
task, which is multi
app means this task need
to jump across multiple apps.
And they have the 268, which
is roughly 70% is a single app.
And in those tasks, some of
them, which is roughly 20%
is through the other
data set like WebArena.
Other data special
here is we also add
the 30 tasks,
which is infeasible
because agent should also know
how to say no to the user.
So we think adding
the infeasible task is
important to make it more
comprehensive for the scenarios
testing.
And we also have a small number
of 43 tasks for Windows, not
just on Ubuntu.
And as I said, because we
think in this example based
on the evaluation
script, it's very
important for the real world
evaluation on multimodal agents.
We construct the 134
evaluation script
on 369 example, the samples.
So you can see the
ratio is very big.
So here is some examples
we sampled from our 300
sets of our benchmark.
So you can see they
are very diverse.
The apps and the cost
different the user intents.
So we compared our benchmark
with the current existing
popular benchmarks from
the different perspective,
such as whether it provides
the controllable executable
environment or whether it's easy
to scale to the new environment,
or it can support
the multimodal,
or whether it could be the
cross app task, or a value
equal to the start task from the
intermediate, the initial state,
and so on.
So we can see our benchmark
is to have more powerful--
I mean, recover
different the scenarios,
the request as a benchmark
for the multi-modal agents.
In right side, we also
did some analysis,
how complicated the task
in the OSWorld benchmark.
We did some comparison
with the WebArena.
So the blue is WebArena and
the yellow is the OSWorld.
The median completion time for
WebArena is roughly 30-40s.
And for OSWorld, the median
completion time is roughly 100,
maybe 110 seconds.
And they also have some
significant number of examples,
maybe need even more.
You will need 900
seconds or even more.
So it means that the complexity
of the expansion market
is also higher than the
existing benchmarks.
After we create the benchmark,
we test the benchmark
with the state of the art, the
LLM, or VLM from the open-source
and also closed-source
foundation models, like GPT 4,
Gemini, cloud, et cetera.
And the left side is
the prompt we used.
We designed four
different testing settings
based on different observation.
The one is only
half accessibility,
which could be the MM
can directly to write.
And the second one is
a online screenshot,
which is pure vision.
And the third one is the
screenshot plus accessibility.
And the fourth one
is a set of mocks.
We did some simplification
on accessibility
because usually
accessibility is very long
and include a lot of
redundant information.
So we did some
simplification to reduce
them to shorten the length
of this text representation.
So this is the result--
the numbers we get.
Let's do some explanation
some analysis on this table.
So first, let's see, at
the bottom of this table
is the human performance.
Roughly, 70% to
75% success rate.
And if you go to see the
performance of the state of art
open-source and the frontier
closed-source model,
it's still far behind--
far from the real human
performance on those
daily use tasks.
It's not like a super hard task.
It's a daily use tasks.
And second, you see
a form different
than the other scenarios.
Human performance
is kind of stable
and it's a plus/minus
that 3% to 5%.
But for those frontier models,
that's large foundation models,
the performance
change dramatically.
And even the model from
same company, for example.
in a set of mock, the
GPT 4V and GPT 4o,
the performance gap is huge.
It's 10% in gap,
given the performance,
since the performance
only just 20% or 10% cap.
So this table's result,
we get last year.
And this year they
have new models
from those vendors, the
OpenAI and Anthropic.
They have some big
improvement on there.
But still, it's far away
from the human performance.
We'll see.
We did some analysis
on what factors that
influence this the performance.
So first, we did some analysis
on the screenshot resolution.
So in the y-axis
is a success rate.
And the x-axis is the
downsampling rate.
So because of BRM, most of them
is still very small resolution.
Not very small, but
it's comparing now,
we have better resolution,
but usually the way
I'm not trained at
the full resolution
is trained on a smaller one.
So we do some downsampling
on the resolution
and then we calculate,
then we run a evaluation.
In the GPT 4 way screenshot,
as you improve the screenshot,
it will get a
better performance.
But in the SOM, I think
the trend still is improve.
But still, this is a noise here.
But it's still improved not
as clear as the screenshot.
I think it's because SOM encoder
have some extra information,
it gets from the
accessibility tree,
based on some text
information inside.
So it decreases the
impact of the resolution.
And then, we're also doing
some analysis on how much
the historic context will
influence the final performance.
So we choose different number
of the trajectory length.
We found in the GPT
4, SOM is improved
as you add more and more
the historical information,
the Stats.
But in the screenshot
one, it doesn't.
It even make it worse.
We think maybe it's because
the SOM have-- like I said,
it includes both the information
from the text, representation,
and accessibility.
And our aim with the
current foundation model
is perform better on the text
rather than the original image.
So we think that is the reason
it's getting better and better
with more and more context.
But for the screenshot
is getting worse.
I think it still is because all
the column the foundation model
is not be well trained for
the computer use scenarios.
So it means it still have a gap.
The open-source community or
the closed-source companies
need to improve the vision
capabilities in the foundation
model if we want to get a better
multimodal agent for computer
use.
And in the right side,
it's a dense distribution
of the accessibility tree.
So although you can
add more and more
nodes text representation
in the multimodal agent
and it can get
better performance.
But they all have the issue
that the accessibility tree
is super long.
So roughly, it's at the 90%
percentile, it's the 6k.
So if we want to add more
of the history context,
then we need to find a way
to get the more simplified
or to call it more concise
accessibility tree.
So maybe they have
some work on how
to select the
relevant information
in the accessibility tree
before you fit into the system.
But when you do this
step, maybe your system
will be slow because you need
this information to maybe
you need to train another big
model to do this information
processing on that added
the extra latency there.
And we also analyze
the model performance
on the Ubuntu and the Windows.
We found that their
correlation is pretty high 0.7.
So which means we could
use the OSWorld framework.
It will be effective.
If you can test your
model in one scenario,
it should be
effectively transferred
to another environment.
And we also did some ablation.
Like, if when we
change the polarization
size of the windows in a
different app, in the screen,
the results also
show very different,
which means that the
foundation model is not
very robust for this
type of the disturbance.
So through this we can
find a lot of theories
that have a lot of work
we need to improve.
And a good news
is, recently they
have a lot of new
progress in these areas.
Anthropic-- they have this new
cloud 3.5 and also the 3.7.
And we can see the very
significant improvement
from here 14%, 15% to 22%.
But still far away
from human 72%.
Of course, if you increase the
number of steps from 15 to 50,
it's getting better.
But it'll still have a big gap.
And the OpenAI also
have this new model
called operator, the COD.
And in their recent
performance, we
can see OpenAI is significantly
better than the cloud 3.5.
And at the 200 step,
they can get even
a 38%, of comparing with, maybe
only have 15% four months ago.
So it's improved super fast.
But if you have 200 steps, most
of the task in the OSWorld,
can be solved on the
15 or even 20 steps.
So which means they still
have a big improvement,
but they have big space to
improve the multimodal agent
for this computer use.
So this is through
the environment
and the benchmark discussion.
We have made a lot
of great progress
on this computer use areas
for multimodal agent.
But still, they have a lot of
the stuff we need to improve.
They still have a lot
of opportunities there.
Now, after this, let's
go to the data part,
since we still need the
data to train our model.
To follow agent
training, I think
we have a bigger challenge
than we do in the training.
Why?
because the agent model
is not a single step.
It's a multi-step.
It's a trajectory.
Collecting the trajectory
data is super expensive.
And the second
is, it's very hard
directly to get the trajectory
data by crawling the internet.
And second, even you say
you have enough money,
I can just to hire
people to collect data.
But to do those annotation
to calculate trajectory data,
it's very time consuming and
it limits the scalability.
Not good for the scaling law.
The cost and the time consuming
of the data collection
through human, and also there's
no free large scale trajectory
purpose you can crawl.
Then what should we do?
Why don't we like the model?
So here I want to
discuss this paper called
The Agenttrek, which is
to synthesize the agent
trajectories through
this guiding play way.
A strategy with a web tutorial.
So what does it mean?
So first, we know they
have a large collection
of tutorial like
text in the internet.
And those text, they
provide the step
by step guidance on how to
perform different tasks.
So we read those
tutorials to learn
how to interact
with different apps
and complete different tasks
in our GUI environments.
And then, those tutorials, they
cover different the scenarios.
So we could systematically
do filtering or filtering
those instruction contents
from the internet.
And of course, those
data is not that clean
because it's written for human.
So they have a lot of
noise, text, descriptions,
and of course,
HTML formats there.
So we need to extract the
valuable knowledges, the steps
from those tutorial
like text and then
transform those unstructured
text into a structured agent
trajectories with the
definition or high level
description of the task that
make it to allow the agent
to use, to train, and mimic
the human task completion.
So in the agent trick, they have
the three stages to do this.
The first stage is called the
automatic tutorial collection
from the internet.
So in this step, I just
roughly described these tracks
and the filter loads tutorial
data from the internet.
You've seen a bunch of heuristic
filtering and some classifier,
like with the fasttext,
and then transform it
into some structured
format with using ARM.
And the step two is the guided
replay for those trajectory
generation, which is using VLM,
vision language model agent,
to execute those tutorials based
on this structured tutorial--
the structure steps--
and run it step by step.
And through that we were
to collect the high level
trajectories, including the high
level description of the task,
the observation of each step,
and the reasoning of each step
and the final actions.
And then, given those data, we
will run a separate evaluator
to evaluate to assess the
quality of the trajectory
to filter out some bad
trajectories or low quality ones
to maintain to ensure
this the effectiveness
of this data for the trainees.
And the step three is we need to
verify those agents by training
a model and fine tune
for the agent models
to demonstrate the improvements
and the significant performance
improvement across
different benchmarks.
So that is roughly a step for
three stages for the agent
trick.
So let me describe
these three steps.
Let's go a little bit
deeper about each step.
The first step is that
it's a tutorial collection
from internet.
So we start from some the large
corpus like a Pajama, DCM.
Then we did using
some filtering with
based on keywords or
some structural features.
And after this step, we
filter maybe 99% of data.
And then, for the
remaining data,
we extract a subset of
the remaining data--
the filtered data-- and use
the LLM to do some annotation.
And it is a good data is
a bad data as a tutorial.
And then after this annotation,
we trained a fasttext classifier
and use that one to classify
all the filter data.
And when you get the tutorial
data, we run another round of M
to paraphrase those data to
follow some predefined format
that used for the guided or
guided plan for the stage Ii.
So this is the.
This is the data flow
for the step one,
when you do the preparatory.
So you can see we use
some the heuristic filters
to do the first step.
The data filtering.
And you can see that just after
this 1, 2, 3-- the sixth step,
it will filter out
more than 99.9% data.
And after you get
this filtered data,
we select a small
number of the data
and use the prompt
ARM to classify it
as a DIY tutorial or not.
So this is the prompt we use.
After we do that, we also have
the human to sample some of them
to verify.
We find that the F1
score is pretty high.
It's like eight.
They can get roughly
88%, 89% And we
find, for some long
text or the documents,
the M is performed
better than the human
when they embed the tutorial
in the long context,
which is the normal,
which is not surprise.
So initially, we
watch after the LLM
on the long text classification.
Then after we filter
those tutorial data,
then we formalize
the tutorial data
into a specific
structured format
that we want to use for the
model, for the guided replay.
Here, we are organized.
So the left side is the prompt.
We used the goal.
So we want to act
through this prompt.
We want to convert the
tutorial into five parts.
First is the platform and
the target environment
that specify what
is the operating
system, what software versions.
So that will be used
for the initial state.
And second one is
the task description
to provide concise
problem statement, which
is the instruction.
The third one is
the prerequisites,
which requires the dependencies,
background knowledges.
And fourth one is this
step by step instructions,
which include this reasoning
guidance and the command syntax.
And the last one is
the expected outcome,
which is used for the
verification or success
indicators.
So after we get this, after
we paraphrase the tutorial,
then we get this
structured tutorial.
And then, we create a VM
agent and fit into this step
by step tutorial.
And the agent will start
to run the interact
with the environment step by
step through this observation
action loop.
And after the
whole execution, we
will recorded all the
observation, action,
intermediate reasoning,
and the whole trajectories.
And then, those will fit
into another VM evaluator
to assess the quality or
correctness of the trajectory
and ensure we got a
high quality data.
So here is an example of the
final version of the data
after you doing all those steps.
So you could see the left side
is the observation sequence,
and right side including
the action, the source,
for each step and the
action code for each step.
So comparing the data we
collect using the agent
trick with the prior
works, the parallels,
the data set people
use to trained model.
First, our data could
be that the agent
can collect much more data.
Here we showed this 10k.
10k is not the a maximum.
We just do some of them.
It could be much bigger.
And the second, complexity
of the data is not low.
Actually, it's pretty good.
The average step is 12 steps.
And you also will have a
lot of the information.
You will have HTML.
You will have accessibility.
You also will have
reasoning your support.
You could get videos,
you can get screenshots,
and you can cover
different websites.
So the Agenttrek
trick is to maintain
the diversity and the realism
because it's from real world.
And it's also adjusting
the scalability issues
that the human annotated data
may have given the budget.
So here is the distribution
of the trajectories.
The left side is the different
number of trajectories
from different websites.
And the right side is
from the high level
different vertical,
different domains, what's
the distribution in the data.
So you can see how the
coverage of the data
set, the domains through
in the Agenttrek.
I mean to say that the data
set created by the agency.
Like we said, we
fine tune the model
to track the performance to see
how good this synthesized data
comparing with other
human annotated data
in the benchmarks, to train
the agent in the benchmarks.
So we did it on this comparison
on the WebArena data set
benchmark.
And the models trained on
Agenttrek data significantly
outperform both, I think,
open-source and even
close-source GPT 4o
models, which demonstrate
the synthesized trajectories.
It's also high
quality and it also
can use to train
the better model.
This is about how we do use
the Agenttrek to do the data
synthesis for the GUI agent.
I think I'll take away
from this Agenttrek work.
It's leveraging the
internet corpus,
is still an important way
because they have a diverse task
resources.
And the second is, with the
reasoning and the reflection,
it's very important--
the factor for the trajectory
which we will talk about
in the model side later.
But however, they still
have an issue here,
because for each
instruction, you still
only get a single
trajectory, which
is an issue that, not like you
only have a single solution
for each query.
It could have
multiple instruction.
So you still have
this issue here,
because it's only the
imitation learning process.
But I think we have the solution
for it because it always work.
So you can use Agenttrek to
create a data for SFT training.
And then you can use the
high level instruction
and run it in the OSWorld for
the second stage the I/O train.
And then, you can solve this
exploitation exploration
process.
So we try to answer the question
like we can use the data
synthesis to make the existing
real vision language model,
we perform better on
the GUI agent tasks.
So the next I want
to discuss is,
when you do data synthesis
to improve this action core
capability for agent
of work external task?
How about it could also
help for the task itself,
like understanding?
We know the vision
language model is
trained for the understanding.
And if we want to do it,
can we crawl from web data?
It's a website that
have this type of data.
I think the answer
is, not really.
Then how can we synthesize?
So first let me see
why we need to do it?
Why we want to
synthesize this type
of action data for
multimodal LLM to understand?
The understanding should be
the capability or skills.
It should have.
But actually, it's not perfect,
or it's far from perfect
on the open-source model.
So here is the four
examples from the four
different perspectives
to explain why we need
the model, who itself
can do the action calling
to improve understanding.
All those tasks, either they
need more fine grained vision
capability, or they need
some reasoning capabilities,
or they need some
external knowledge.
So here we introduce a TACO,
which is through synthesize this
Chain-of-Thought-and-Action
data to improve the multimodal
understanding capability through
adding this action calling
capabilities,
skills in the model.
So this is some
examples, we showed
after adding this action
calling capability which
is trained through the synthetic
data we will discuss later.
It can generate the
thoughts and the actions
through the observations.
They will do again until
they get the results.
So this is the one
example we just showed,
it failed in this model.
And this another one is
called the localization
and the functions, which
are visual functions.
And this is to query the
external knowledge, the text
knowledge, the knowledge
observation model only.
And this makes the region OCR
and calculate the capabilities.
So let's go back, how we
create the synthetic pipeline
to generate this
data for the CoTA?
There is a lot of details
here but don't worry.
I'll explain them one by one.
It's not that complicated.
So first, for this data
synthesis pipeline,
they have two parts.
First part is called the
model based generation.
And the bottom part is the
programmatic generation.
So in a model based
generation, first we
take the existing the image QA.
We get those image and
the QA pairs as input,
and we prompt the
frontier models.
Let's say, you have this
image and the QA pair
that generate the train
of thought and action.
Given those action or
called action list,
or train of thought
if they do not
have the relevant action
in the list, other then
it will generate.
Now, after the generate below
the train of thought with action
or thought without
action, then we
will verify the
outcome, the output.
If it is correct,
then we will pass it.
If it's not, then we
will convert this pair
as the direct answer pairs.
So in this way, you
will get the data.
Not all of them have the action.
Some of them have action.
Some of them only have train
of thought, some of them
without this direct answer.
So that is this
part-- the top part.
And then the bottom part, we do
the programatical generation.
This way, we do not
have the QA pairs
in this programmatic
generation process.
So we only have the image.
Then we use the model without
maybe the detection model,
depth model, OCR model,
and different models.
And also, it could be human
to label some data, some box.
And we get those dense
annotations in the image.
And we design some
manual templates.
And they use that to
generate the QA pairs.
And through that one
we can synthesize
what actions in the formula
answer to question to answer.
So this is the
template we use to do
the programmatic generation.
So some of them is
about the content.
Some of them is about the 2D
spatial reasoning or 3D spatial
reasoning.
Some of them is the mixed
understanding and the counting.
So we try to mimic the different
reasoning or the action
call needed to answer different
type of the questions.
And then here, the bottom,
is the action sets,
which cover like OCR, get
object localization and depth
estimation, and club
regular zoom in,
and the query language model,
accurate solve math equation
is really pretty diverse.
So we go through this two way.
We collect the data.
And of course in this
data, we have some of them
is the train of
thought action data.
Some of them is not.
Then we need to do some
analysis on the data
and test on the benchmarks.
So first one, through
our experiment,
we found, to get the
multi-modal foundation
models, to have this reasoning
or action core capabilities,
you need to use fine tuning.
In the result we found if few
shot or in context learning,
it doesn't work.
And the second is, we
finally have compelling
for the tasks with this action.
Adding this action
capabilities is really
to improve the capability
to solve the task.
It cannot solve before we
improve the understanding
capabilities, which means
that even understanding this
capability is also could be
enhanced by adding external
tools and make it through this
function call or two calling
to improve it.
Which is not a
surprise, but it's also
interesting to see
this positive results.
So it can give us a
different, another direction
that are, how could we improve
our models on understanding?
And this is the
second observation.
We find the best COT data.
So the COT data, the best
one, which can almost
test on the different
scenarios that you see,
it has on this A, OK, VV, QA,
Blink, maps with time MMU.
It's almost improve
all the tasks which
means that adding this action
capability in a data set, that
also act to create this
train of thought action data,
it can improve with this data.
To train the model to
the multimodal model,
it can improve the model
understanding capability
in general, not just improve
one model, one benchmark.
And the third observation
from the TACO experiments
on the COT, the train
of thought action data
set, we find the quality is
more important than quantity.
Not just add more, you will
get a better performance.
So this paper is talk about how
we could add in the action core
capability into the multimodal
language model or foundation
model.
And first you need
to fine tune a model,
not through the few shot.
And second is, COT data
is consistent to improve
those models through
this fine tuning
on this instruction,
this synthesized data.
And the fourth one
is the quality.
It's more important than
quantity, which is not new.
It's some lessons we
learned from here.
So here, we have discussed about
the environment benchmarking
and the data synthesis.
I think now you already
have the comprehensive view,
holistic view about
this multi-agent areas.
If you want to test
the agent, if you
want to generate the data.
And if you want to do the
I/O in the environment,
you already have those
tools and you can start
to create your multimodal.
So the last one, I want
to spend some time talking
about the model.
Although, I'm not saying
that this is the best model,
but I think maybe you can
learn from some insights
from this model.
I think so right now, I
really have new models.
So there's always
have a better one.
So I hope like we can
discuss some different things
about the model here.
So I want to discuss
this paper is Aguvis--
our paper, which is
a unified pure vision
model for the GI agent.
For the GI agents,
we finally have
three issues we want to solve.
First is, most of GI
agent is text based--
text representation
like accessibility tree.
Second, the visual grounding
and performance capability
is not good.
I think it's because
most of the model
not really to train the
model for the computer use.
And third one is
most of the model
is to generate an action
directly without reason.
So here is some more concrete
slides about this three
observation or issues.
The first one, you
can see, they have
different the textual
representation.
Some like Web,
HTML, maybe DOM 3.
And in the OS, they have another
type of accessibility and model
have different ones.
And most of them is super
long, super lengthy.
And it could be
longer and longer
as the complexity
of your device.
So comparing with the
vision by pure vision-based,
vision is just one.
So whatever your background code
looks like, the image is same.
So that is one and about
the benefit of the GUI.
The second one is, because
of different system use
different tools, the action
space is very different.
It's not a big issue, but it's
still a issue that it will
prevent this effective
course development learning,
and also that you cannot
leverage different training data
together, which not good
for the scalability.
Then it's this visual
grounding capability.
So here we tested on the mobile,
desktop, and web scenarios.
We found that those
close-source model performance
surprising bad, I would say.
So it means the model doesn't
really optimize for the computer
use scenarios.
Then this is typically
for the new one operator
or cloud 3.5, 3.7 model.
And here is an example,
the existing methods,
they train the agent to generate
the low-level actions directly
like this.
The pi, the director
of the code,
rather than the sophisticated,
the reasoning concept,
reasoning the text,
which would make
to get those models
or those agents
very struggle on the
complex scenarios
in the real world, that may
require more careful planning.
Those planning
knowledge could be
transferred from the text
corpus, which trained in the ARM
before.
So given these three issues,
we propose this Arguvis model.
First, is the pure vision based.
So it doesn't matter what
is the accessibility tree
format it's using in a
system or in a web browser.
And the second is, if we improve
the grounding model through
combined we defined a
new unified form format.
We combine all the existing
data and train the model
to improve the grounding.
And the third one
is, we explicitly
to include this
reasoning process.
And what we call
the inner monologue
into our training and the
model training for the action
generation.
As I said, for the Arguvis,
we eliminate this dependencies
on the platform specific
textual representation
because it is pure vision based.
It's directly operated
on the screen images.
So it makes the model
more generalizable
into different interface.
And we did develop a
standardized action space
that we could combine
the different data set
into the same action format so
that we can leverage more data--
the existing data.
And the more crucial
is-- the right side
is-- we incorporate this inner
monologue during the training,
which can develop this
sophisticated rhythm
patterns, which
through by leveraging
the knowledge of
memory patterns,
is already memorized in the ARM.
I think this is important to
build more robust action model.
So in each interaction
step our agent
were to generate this in the
monologue, the two step, two
component, the two
parts-- the salt
and the low level instructions,
between the visual observation
and the final actions.
So through this
salt and low level
instruction and the action,
you can consider this.
This enables the agent
and do it step by step
from the complexity.
Because at the beginning you
get a high level instruction
and you're doing this
train of thought.
So you decompose the problem
into some small steps.
And with those steps,
you can do generate
this low-level instruction
for each step about action.
And then you can get
a better concrete code
to access question.
So then it could make the agent
be more robust, more accurate.
So that is the motivation.
For the training
we have two step.
First step is the grounding
and the second step
is the planning
and the reasoning.
And for grounding, we
did some tricks, which
is grounding packing strategy.
What do you mean grounding
packing strategy?
We want to find all the
grounding pairs, the grounding
samples, which based
on the same image,
and we concatenate them
as a multi-turn grounding.
As one sample, we found that can
improve the training efficiency
and even to have a big
improvement on the performance.
And in the second
stage is, we add
this in the monologue
in our training, which
make the agent to generate
this intermediate thoughts
and the low level instructions
before they generate action
directly.
In the data part, as
I said, because it's
a pure vision
based, we can easily
to combine the different
data sets together and define
same format for the outcome.
Then we can leverage
most of the existing data
and create a new data
set to train our model.
And for the monologue we prompt
the frontier model as a GPT 4o,
Given the observation
image and highlight
UI element with the
instruction, and the final goal,
and the final action code, and
the bountiful gift for all,
to generate in the
monologue component.
So this is an example
of pivotal previous
is they have the
forms, instruction,
and previous action.
Of course, the observation
is we don't add here.
And this action then
later after this step,
we will have the thought and
the low-level instructions
in a new training data.
So this way we create the
Arguvis collection which
is combined a number
of different data sets.
But then, we finally
get for stage one.
We get the one million
the GUI grounding data.
And for stage two we get the
35k multi-step tragectery,
with this explicit
monologue reasoning data--
it's great.
And then, we do the same
thing like we did before.
We run our model.
We train our model on this
ancient Arguvis collection
data set.
And we demonstrate-- we show
that this Arguvis model performs
exceptional on the
grounding task.
So the top is the
So it has no plan.
And we can see the
significant output
from the existing
models on those tasks.
And we also run the
two stage training.
So we also have the single model
to both grounding and planning
reasoning action.
And we found that after you
did the second stage training,
it even improved
this grounding task
and achieve the state
of the art performance.
And then, we also did the
development evaluation
on the offline
setting on Matlab.
It also showed it achieved
the superior performance
across different metrics
on the offline set
and also on the Android setting.
We also did this evaluation
on the online setting,
which is a Mind2Web
and the Android world,
which is this Mind2Web guide.
With different Mind2Web,
it provides a dynamic web
based environment to
do the evaluation.
And we can see the performance
of how the archivist models
the superior performance.
And even better than so.
And the one thing I
want to emphasize is,
if you see that here is the
Arguvis 70 model with GPT 4o
planar.
It performed state
of art in this tasks,
which means that the Arguvis
model have a better grounding
capabilities.
And this definitely can
improve the final performance
of this planar task.
And also, we found
they still have
a big space for
grinding to improve,
to which will improve
the final performance
on the different computer use.
And we do some analysis
for different components
in the Arguvis performance.
Both stage one and stage two
is important in the model.
It's also very crucial
for both the high level
reasoning and the low
level grounded tasks.
And we find that,
in the monologue,
actually helps to solve
the harder task, which
in the right side, you see why
is self plan wise in force plan.
In force plan means, it must
generate in the monologue.
And it can achieve
the 20% of resolve,
20% of the grinding errors.
And the left, that
is two examples
with and without in the model.
And we also see the
cross-platform benefits
in the Arguvis.
The Arguvis is trained on
the web and mobile data.
OSWorld is a computer use.
We find it remarkable,
although we didn't try
and exclusively on the
computer use scenario,
the model still
perform pretty good.
And with using Arguvis 70 to
be as a grounding plus before,
it's even better than
how a computer use model.
So here, you can
take away is, first--
the Arguvis model is
a unified framework.
It can perform pretty robust
across different platforms
with only visual observation.
And I think the visual--
this pure vision paradigm--
have a big advantages on
the computer use or GUI use
case, which I think
OpenAI already agree with.
This is my comment because
they have the operator.
And the second is, although
they have a lot of progress,
we still need to
improve both grounding
and the structural reasoning.
Don't just try to
improve reasoning.
Actually, they
have bigger space.
There you need to improve
in the grounding side.